pozible.com 2016-04-08

# Privacy Policy | Pozible

Your privacy is very important to us. You must read and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy before becoming a Pozible account holder. As part of the normal operation of our services we collect, use and, in some cases, disclose information about you to third parties. This Privacy Policy governs the information we collect about you and your use of information we provide to you. By accepting this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in the manner prescribed in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the Pozible User Agreement. 

Although this may seem long, we have prepared a detailed policy because we believe you should know as much as possible about our practices so that you can make an informed decision. The privacy practices of this notice apply to the website located at [http://www.pozible.com](http://www.pozible.com/) (collectively the "Site"). Pozible is subject to the requirements of applicable law. We strive to provide a consistent set of privacy practices throughout our Pozible trading community. 

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to Pozible by sending email to [admin@pozible.com](mailto:admin@pozible.com). 

This Privacy Policy contains a number of references to other information pages on our Site and other websites. Please note: underlined words and phrases are click-through links to these pages and websites. Pozible strongly recommends that as you read this Privacy Policy, you click on such links to obtain further important details about the Privacy Policy, as they may contain further terms and conditions which apply to you as a Pozible account holder. 

**1\. An Important Note About Children.** Children (persons under the age of 18 years) are not eligible to use our services unsupervised and we ask that children do not submit any personal information to us. If you are under the age of 18 years, you can use this service only in conjunction with and under the supervision of your parents or guardians. 

**2\. Information We Collect** Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, safe and customised trading experience. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customise our services to make your experience safer and easier. We only collect personal information about you that we consider necessary for this purpose and to achieve this goal. 

To fully use our services, you will need to register using our online registration form, where you will be required to provide us with your contact information and other personal information. You are required to provide us with your full name. Under some circumstances we may require some additional necessary financial information, such as, but not limited to: if you are registering using an email account at a free email service, or posting a project on our site. We use your financial information, including credit card information to verify your name, address, and other contact information. 

We automatically track certain information about you based upon your behaviour on our Site. We use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve you and our community. This information is compiled and analysed on an aggregated basis. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our Site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our Site or not), what browser you are using, and your IP address. 

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of our Site. "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing customised services. We also offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie". We also use "cookies" to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can also help us provide information which is targeted to your interests. Cookies are stored on your hard drive, not on our Site. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted at the end of a session. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on our Site and you may be required to re-enter your password more frequently during a session. 

Additionally, you may encounter "cookies" or other similar devices on certain pages of our Site that are placed by third parties. For example, if you view a web page created by a user, there may be a "cookie" placed within that web page. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties. 

If you choose to post a project or support a project on our Site, we collect information about your trading behaviour. We also collect other users' comments about you. 

If you are a project creator with us, we may choose to collect some additional necessary information, including billing address, credit card number and credit card expiration date and bank account details. 

If you choose to post messages in our site or other message areas or leave feedback for other users, we will collect and store such information that you disclose to us. 

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you. 

If you register for Pozible on another web site or use a web site providing a service for Pozible or a web site that helps facilitate your activity on Pozible, that web site may provide personal information about you and your transactions back to Pozible. 

Payment Information is transmitted securely using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology and processed through a secure third party payment gateway (PCI DSS Compliant). Pozible does not store your payment information (such as credit card or debit card information) on Pozible servers or databases.

**This website uses the Google AdWords remarketing service** AdWords Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google. It connects the activity of www.pozible.com with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie. You can opt out of the cookie tracking here: <http://google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en>

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. Place of processing: USA. – Find the [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

**3\. Our Use of Your Information** We use personal information about you (including but not limited to the information in the file we maintain about you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Site) to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, help ensure safe trading on our Site, and enforce our User Agreement. At times, we may look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes, and in particular we may examine your information to identify users using multiple Usernames or aliases. 

If you choose to post a project on our Site, we use your address and billing information to bill you and provide associated support. 

You agree that we may use personal information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyse site usage, to improve our content and product offerings and customise our Site's content, layout, and services. These uses improve our Site and better tailor it to meet your needs, so as to provide you with a smooth, efficient, safer and customised experience while using our services. 

You agree that we may use your information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests, such as administrative notices, product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of the Site. By accepting the User Agreement and Privacy Policy you expressly agree to receive this information. 

**4\. Our Disclosure of Your Information** Although Pozible uses industry standard practices to protect your personal information, due to technical limitations, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances (further details of which are set out below in the "Legal Requests" section), or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we cannot and do not guarantee, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. 

As a matter of policy, we do not sell or rent any personal information about you to any third party. However, the following describes some of the ways that your personal information may be disclosed, and by agreeing to the User Agreement and Privacy Policy you expressly agree that your personal information may be disclosed by Pozible in the following ways: 

Partners. We aggregate (gather up data across all user accounts) personal information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to partners and other third parties for marketing and promotional purposes. However, in these situations, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to identify you personally. Certain information, such as your name, email address, password, credit card number, and bank account number, are never disclosed to advertisers. 

Pozible Community. Throughout the Site, you are identified by your full name. If you select your email address as your full name you will disclose your email address to other users and third parties. As a result, other users and third parties might send you unsolicited email and be able to personally identify all of your activities on the Site. Even if your full name is not your email address, your full name can be used to identify you and your activities throughout the Site. Other people can see the projects that you have supported in the past, associated comments, your postings on the Site, and so on. We also provide a number of ways to allow other users to find more out about you and your Site activities, such as our feature that allows users to quickly see all of the projects you have created and supported at the time. If you are involved in a transaction, we allow other users to view your full name, email address and obtain your contact information. 

External Service Providers. There are a number of services offered by external service providers that help you use our Site (e.g., co-branded sites, listing agents, authentication, mediation). If you choose to use these optional services, disclose personal information to the external service providers, and/or grant them permission to collect personal information about you, then their use of your personal information is governed by their privacy policy. We may, for your convenience, provide some of your personal information to the external service provider offering such services. However, before we disclose your personal information to an external service provider, you will have the opportunity to see what data is about to be sent and have the ability to approve the disclosure. To prevent our disclosure of your personal information to an external service provider, you can decline such disclosures or simply not use their services. Because we do not control the privacy practices of these third parties, you should evaluate their practices before deciding to use their services. 

Internal Service Providers. We may use internal service providers to facilitate our services (e.g., search, discussion boards, surveys) and therefore we may provide some of your personal information directly to them. In some instances, the internal service provider may collect information directly from you (such as the situation where we ask an internal service provider to conduct a survey for us). In these cases, you will be notified of the involvement of the internal service provider, and all information disclosures you make will be strictly optional. In all cases, the information we supply the internal service providers is restricted by confidentiality agreements. If you provide additional information to an internal service provider directly, then their use of your information is governed by their applicable privacy policy. 

Other Corporate Entities. We share much of our data, including personal information about you, with Pozible companies & joint ventures that are committed to serving your online trading needs and related services, as allowed by applicable law. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. Our subsidiaries and joint ventures follow privacy practices no less protective of all users than our practices described in this Privacy Policy, to the extent allowed by applicable law. It is possible that Pozible, subsidiaries, its joint ventures, or any combination of such, could merge with or be acquired by another business entity. Should such a combination occur, you should expect that Pozible would share some or all of your information in order to continue to provide the service. You will receive notice of such event (to the extent it occurs) as provided in Section 11 ("Notice") we will require that the new combined entity follow the practices disclosed in this Privacy Policy. 

Legal Requests. Pozible may lawfully disclose your personal information for law enforcement or regulatory purposes. Pozible cooperates with law enforcement inquires and other third parties to enforce laws, intellectual property and other rights. We can (and you authorise us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other governmental officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary, appropriate or as otherwise permitted under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, piracy or other activity that is illegal or may expose us to legal liability. 

**5\. Your Use of Other Users' Information** In order to facilitate interaction among all Pozible community members, our service allows you limited access other users' contact information. As a project creator you have access to the full names, email address and other contact information of the project supporter and as a supporter you have access to the full name, email address and other contact information of the creator. 

By entering into our User Agreement, you agree that, with respect to other users' personal information that you obtain through the Site or through a Pozible-related communication or Pozible-facilitated transaction, Pozible hereby grants to you a license to use such information only for: 

Pozible-related communications that are not unsolicited commercial messages, using cobranded services offered through Pozible (e.g. insurance, shipping and fraud complaints), and any other purpose that such user expressly opts into after adequate disclosure of the purpose(s). 

In all cases, you must give users an opportunity to remove themselves from your database and a chance to review what information you have collected about them. In addition, under no circumstances, except as defined in this Section, can you disclose personal information about another user to any third party without our consent and the consent of such other user after adequate disclosure. Note that law enforcement personnel and other rights holders are given different rights with respect to information they access. 

We and our users do not tolerate spam. Therefore, without limiting the foregoing, you are not licensed to add a Pozible user, even a user who has purchased an item from you, to your mail list (email or physical mail) without their express consent after adequate disclosure. To report spam from other Pozible users, please send an email to [admin@pozible.com](mailto:admin@pozible.com). 

**6\. Use of Email Tools** You may not use the send a message service or other email forwarding services that we offer to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our User Agreement or Privacy Policy. 

**7\. Control of Your Password** You are responsible for all actions taken with your password, including fees. Therefore we do not recommend that you disclose your Pozible password to any third parties. If you choose to share your password or your information with third parties to provide you additional services, you agree that you are responsible for all actions taken with your password and therefore you should review that third party's privacy policy. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password as detailed in Section 8. 

**8\. Accessing, Reviewing and Changing Your Personal Information** Following registration, you can review and change the information you submitted during registration including: 

Your registration information such as: name, company, address, city, state, post code, country, primary phone number, secondary phone number, fax number and gender. 

Your password (if you have supplied such information). 

You must promptly update your personal information if it changes. Once posted, you cannot change or remove any public postings made in our forums or other message areas or the feedback area. 

Upon your request, we will deactivate your account, contact information, and financial information from our active databases. To make this request, email the [admin@pozible.com](mailto:admin@pozible.com). Such information will be deactivated as soon as reasonably possible in accordance with our deactivation policy and applicable law. 

We will retain in our files information you have requested to remove in some circumstances, such as to prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, and enforce our User Agreement, and to comply with legal requirements. Further, such prior information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical constraints and the fact that we back up our systems. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personal information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests. However, such information will be deactivated from public viewing and usage by other members of Pozible and will only be available to select Pozible personnel. 

**9\. Other Information Collectors** Except as otherwise expressly discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties, whether they are project creators or project supporters on our Site or other sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the personal information you disclose to them. To the extent that we use third party advertisers, they adhere to their own privacy customs and policies. Since Pozible does not control the privacy policies of third parties, you are subject to the privacy policies of that third party. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others. 

**10\. Security** Your Information is stored on Pozible's servers currently located in the United States. We use industry standard efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information, such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. 

**11\. Notice** We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time based on your comments and our need to accurately reflect our data collection and disclosure practices. All changes to this policy are effective after we provide you with at least thirty (30) days' notice of the changes by posting the changes on the announcements board and sending email to users who select such notification preference We provide you with thirty (30) days notice to allow you the opportunity to notify Pozible if you do not agree to such changes as described in Section 8. 

If you have any questions, please contact [admin@pozible.com](mailto:admin@pozible.com).
